[Music]
嘿嘿，这里是STH的Patrick
hey guys this is Patrick from STH
今天我们来看看这台来自超微的Intel OPA 48口100G交换机的内部
today we're to look inside a super micro intel omni path 48 port a handred gigabit per second switch
OPA是一个非常有意思的技术，我们会做一系列的视频
now this is a really interesting technology in this part of our series that we're gonna start doing
看看这些不太一样的服务器硬件
taking a look at various server hardware
虽然它们有些没有被广泛应用，但其中也有一些不错的创新技术
platforms that you know really showed a lot of innovation maybe they didn't get a great adoption or maybe they did but
我们只是想给各位看一些在实验室里的有趣的东西
we just kind of wanted to show people some of the things that are in the lab
你们平常可能看不到这样的硬件
that are really cool pieces of hardware that you wouldn't normally see otherwise
好的，让我们来看看Intel Omni Path(OPA)
okay so Intel Omni path so Omni path that was
OPA最低就是100Gbps光纤，以此来和Mellanox主导的InfiniBand还有以太网在高性能计算领域竞争
started as a 100 gate per second fabric to really compete with both InfiniBand which Mellanox was championing as well as Ethernet in the high performance computing space
它有两种部署模式，第一种是标准的PCI-E 3.0x16形式拓展卡
and they're really two ways of this was deployed the first way was on a standard PCIe by 16 gen 3 card
看起来和以太网网卡还有Mellanox IB卡没什么两样的
and now it looks a lot like an Ethernet NIC or a Mellanox InfiniBand adapter but
另一种方法我觉得更好玩一些，我们之前在实验室就见过这样的
the other way I think was a lot more interesting and it's something that we actually saw in the lab
为了让大家给OPA捧场，Intel把OPA光纤网卡集成到了
to get adoption for Omni path Intel actually integrated the Omni path fabric adapter directly on
Xeon phi 的Knight landing以及Knight mill两条产品线里
to chip packages both in the Xeon Phi Knights landing in Knights mil but also
以及cascade lake 的前任，至强可拓展或者叫他skylake
in cascade lake predecessor which was the Intel Xeon scalable SP or skylake
只要多花$155，100G光纤抱回家
and so for about $155 more than these standards SKU you could get a hundred gig fabric connector built in and with
而且还不用为了网卡多花16条PCI-E通道
that also meant was that you didn't have to use PCIe lanes for your hundred gig fabric which takes 16 you could just use
因为它用的是Intel专属PCI-E通达
this because their dedicated PCIe lanes on the package
性价比不错吧
that was awesome and the
Intel也觉得在基础配置上，比如6148上，加$155就能都得到一个集成的网卡真是太划算了
fact that Intel was selling them basically the on package adapters for only like $155 uplift to over a normal SKU like a 6148 that's a big deal
如果一个组织能采用OPA的话，成本能节约很多
because it became a lot cheaper for organizations to use omni path than other fabrics
实际上呢，这个技术用的人还是比较少，很多服务器也不能把这根线从CPU引出到机箱后面
in practice it was still always a little bit funky to use and a lot of server couldn't even get the little cables that would connect from the CPUs to the back of chassis and that was kind
整体的体验上并不是特别好
of a weird little bit from the whole experience but we also didn't see the
Intel也看到了，于是OPA并没有在Intel的cascade lake中出现
Omni path make it into cascade lake so it seems like Intel's doing a reset for
Intel似乎要重置OPA 200系列了
OPA 200 they announced a little bit at
他们在SC18中宣布了这件事，但目前还没有任何消息
supercomputing 18 but we're not really seeing a ton of it now so we hope to see it in the future instead or we're gonna
不管那么多了，我们今天要看的是超微出品的Intel OPA 48口100G交换机
do today is it we're gonna go look at an Intel Omni Path 48
port hundred gigabit per second switch that Super Micro made
虽然是超微生产的，但大部分设计都参照了Intel的参考设计
but a lot of these designs were mostly the Intel reference design that were
或者说Intel只是和合作伙伴一起，做出了这个产品
just produced by their partners okay so
我们先来看产品吧
let's go look at it the actual model that we're looking at is a Super Micro
它的名字是超微SSH-C48Q
SSH-C48Q you can see that there are
你能看到前面板有48个QSFP28接口
48 QSFP28 ports on the front and this
这个QSFP28物理接口和IB和以太网的接口是一样的
is the same q SS p 28 connector that you use for InfiniBand or Ethernet there's
另外还有管理口和USB口
also managed port USB port
接着我们来打开这台交换机看看内部，这才是好戏对吧
but now let's open up the switch and see what's inside because we want to see kind of the cool bits of the switch so
拧开背后的螺丝，抬起盖子
we're gonna just open up the thumb screw on the back and lift the cover off this
这算是个比较好拆的交换机了
is actually a really easy switch to get open
内部...很简洁...或者说简陋
and inside you can see something that's well pretty darn simple sometimes
一般实验室里的初版都非常复杂，非常粗糙
when we get things in the lab they are very complex and they look like pretty rough first versions but this is
但这台看上去非常简洁，只有几个组件
actually a really clean design that only has a few major components since we're
既然我们在交换机的后方，那就先从风扇开始介绍吧
starting at the rear of the chassis I guess it kind of makes sense to look at the fans first and you can see that
这些风扇就是标准的4pin 1u风扇
these are just standard 1u fans they're actually used a four pin pwm power
你在标准的白盒交换机里面都能看到
connector which is standard you need to see that in most white box servers and
这些风扇不是真的热插拔风扇，但也不像普通1u服务器那样
they're not really hot-swap but that's also not overly
common in 1u servers and instead what they have is
他们用这些延长线连接风扇，如果你想更换风扇，从中间就可以断开排线
they have these long extension cables and long extension cables bring power
to each fan and you can snap them in the middle too if you had to replace them
这里是冗余的750w电源
there's also a redundant power supplies this using 750 watt redundant power
这是电源分配板
supplies and there's a power distribution board for those power
以上是交换机的电源和冷却部分
supplies and that's pretty much the cooling and power that's needed for this entire switch which is really not that much
相比于如今的高端200G或者400G交换机，这个配置不算豪华
compared to some of the higher-end 200 400 gig switches that we're seeing these
在这个散热器底下压着交换机是ASIC芯片
days under this big heat sink that's the main switch ASIC for the platform it
它需要消耗大量电力，这就是为什么需要高端的冗余电源
uses a lot of power so that's why we have redundant power we also have pretty high end power supplies you also
还有这里的Molex QSFP28 母口插座
see these molex QSFP28 cages each cage
每个插座都有六个QSFP28接口
has a total of six QSFP28 connectors
8 * 6 = 48 (port)
and there are eight six port connectors so that or cages so that means that gives you 48 ports and in the back we
还有一个有意思的东西是这个小卡
have something that's I think a little bit interesting as well which is this little card
这张卡是管理卡，在很多高端交换机上都有出现
now this little card is something that we see on pretty high end switches and it's a management card so
如果你把它拿下来就能看到上面有CPU、内存
if we actually take the card out you'll see as you see there's a CPU on the area see that there's memory on there and in
在高端交换机里面很多都有一整台电脑运行在里面
higher end switches they actually have entire computers that run inside the switch that do all the management
用来提供管理功能
functions that you would need beyond
而速度超快的ASIC只需要移动数据就行了
just you know the superfast switch ASIC moving data around so this is kind of
这就是交换机的控制面了
cool just to see the control plane of the switch
当我们把这台交换机装在实验室里运行NVMEoF的时候
when this switch was installed in our lab that was running a NVME over fabric we even had an optain nvme
插一嘴，我们在实验室里用傲腾搭建了一个NVMEoF演示场景
over fabric demo setup with it
它运行的很好
it worked really well
因为这东西你平常应该不太能见到
and it's something you don't
所以我就拿它作为我们“牛逼的硬件”系列的开端了
really see a lot so we wanted to bring this as the start to our cool hardware series that we're gonna be doing on sth
谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢谢
thanks for watching if you enjoyed this video you should check out our main site you should subscribe and we're gonna
关注原作者讷！！
have more really cool hardware that we're gonna show you in the near future